<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<anniehall>
	<description lang="en">Interior. Theater Lobby-Day.</description>
	<description lang="en">A lined-up crowd of ticket holders waiting to get into the theater, Alvy and Annie among them. A hum of indistinct chatter can be heard through the ensuing scene.</description>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Loudly to his companion right behind Alvy and Annie) We saw the Fellini film last Tuesday. It is not one of his best. It lacks a cohesive structure. You know, you get the feeling that he’s not absolutely sure what it is he wants to say.’Course, I’ve always felt he was essentially a-a technical film maker. Granted, La Strada was a great film. Great in its use of negative energy more than anything else. But that simple cohesive core… 		Alvy, reacting to the man’s loud monologue, starts to get annoyed while Annie begins to read her newspaper.</man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Overlapping the man’s speech) I’m-I’m-I’m gonna have a stroke.</alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : (Reading) Well, stop listening to him.</annie>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Overlapping Alvy and Annie) You know, it must need to have had its leading from one thought to another. You know what I’m talking about ?</man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Sighing) He’s screaming his opinions in my ear.</alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : Like all that Juliet of the Spirits or Satyricon, I found it incredibly… Indulgent. You know, he really is. 		26</man>
	<description lang="fr">Intérieur. Hall de cinéma. Jour. 		Dans le hall de cinéma empli de conversations, Annie et Alvy sont au milieu de la queue. Derrière eux, un homme baratine sa compagne.</description>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : On a vu le film de Fellini mardi dernier. C’est loin d’être un de ses meilleurs. C’est très lacunaire au plan de la cohésion. Tu sais, on a le sentiment qu’il n’est pas absolument sûr de ce qu’il veut avancer. Au fond, hh… Il m’a toujours paru évident qu’il n’était… Qu’un remarquable technicien. Certes, La Strada a été un grand film. Grand par l’utilisation d’énergie négative à défaut d’autre chose. Mais ce n’est pas cela qui remplace la cohésion. Tu vois ce que je veux dire ? 		Alvy montre des signes d’énervement en entendant les paroles du type, Annie se met à lire le journal. </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Je… Je… Je… Je… Je… Je… Je vais faire un infarctus. </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Ne l’écoute pas, alors ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (il soupire) : Je ne l’écoute pas mais il me corne aux oreilles ! </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : C’est comme dans Juliette des Esprits ou le Satyricon. J’y vois une incroyable complaisance. C’est vrai, il faut oser le dire. C’est même un des cinéastes les plus complaisants. Convenons-en. </man>
	<man lang="en">He’s one of the most indulgent film makers. He really is- ALVY : (Overlapping) Key word here is « indulgent ». </man>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Overlapping) -without getting… Well, let’s put it this way… </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (To Annie, who is still reading, overlapping the man in line who is still talking) What are you depressed about ? Annie : I missed my therapy. I overslept. </alvy>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : How can you possibly oversleep ? </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : The alarm clock. </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Gasping) You know what a hostile gesture that is to me ? </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : I know-because of our sexual problem, right ? ALVY : Hey, you… Everybody on line at the New Yorker has to know our rate of intercourse ? </annie>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : It’s like Samuel Beckett, you know-I admire the technique but he dœsn’t… He dœsn’t hit me on a gut level. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (To Annie) I’d like to hit this guy on a gut level. </alvy>
	<description lang="en">The man in line continues his speech all the while Alvy and Annie talk. </description>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : Stop it, Alvy ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Wringing his hands) Well, he’s spitting on my neck ! You know, he’s spitting on my neck when he talks. </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : And then, the most important thing of all is a comedian’s vision. </man>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : And you know something else ? You know, you’re so egocentric that if I miss my therapy you can think of it in terms of how it affects you ! </annie>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Lighting a cigarette while he talks) Gal gun- shy is what it is. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Reacting again to the man in line) Probably on their first date, right ? </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Still going on) It’s a narrow view. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : Probably met by answering an ad in the New York Review of Books. Thirtyish academic wishes to meet woman. </alvy>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (en aparté) : Hhh. La complaisance est à toutes les sauces. 		(Il s’adresse à Annie, toujours plongée dans son journal) Pourquoi as-tu le moral à plat ? </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : J’ai loupé ma thérapie. Je suis une dormeuse ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Mais enfin, comment peux-tu faire dodo à ce point ? ANNIE : Personne ne « m’éveille ». </alvy>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (il respire bruyamment) : Tu développes là une conduite d’hostilité à mon égard ! </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Évidemment ! À cause de notre problème sexuel, n’est-ce pas ? </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Eh… Tu veux… Tous les mecs qui font la queue doivent-ils connaître notre fréquence coïtale ? </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Prenons Samuel Beckett. Tu sais que j’admire ses procédés, mais voilà un gars qui ne me prend pas du tout aux tripes… Et s’il n’y a pas l’émotion… </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : J’en connais un que je prendrais aux tripes, moi ! ANNIE : Oh ! La paix, Alvy ! </alvy>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (il se tord les mains) : Mais il me postillonne dans le cou ! C’est vrai, il me bavote dans la nuque ! </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE :… Hhhh. Du point de vue du comédien… </man>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : J’ai un autre grief contre toi. Tu sais, tu es un tel égocentrique que si moi, je loupe ma thérapie, tu déclares que c’est toi qui en es le plus affecté ! </annie>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE (glissant une cigarette entre ses lèvres) : C’est une fuite devant… La femme, en réalité. </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Ils en sont à leur premier rencard, derrière, c’est sûr. HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : C’est une vision très étroite du monde. (Suite indistincte) </alvy>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Probablement deux frustrés qui se sont trouvés grâce à une pub passée dans un hebdo de gauche ! 	Who’s interested in Mozart, James Joyce and sodomy. (He sighs ; then to Annie) Whatta you mean, our sexual problem ? </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : Oh ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : I-I-I mean, I’m comparatively normal for a guy raised in Brooklyn. </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : Okay, I’m very sorry. My sexual problem ! Okay, my sexual problem ! Huh ? </annie>
	<man lang="en">The man in front of them turns to look at them, then looks away. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : I never read that. That was-that was Henry James, right ? Novel, uh, the sequel to Turn of the Screw ? My Sexual… </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : (Even louder now) It’s the influence of television. Yeah, now Marshall McLuhan deals with it in terms of it being a-a high, uh, high intensity, you understand ? A hot medium… As opposed to a… </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (More and more aggravated) What I wouldn’t give for a large sock o’horse manure. </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE :… As opposed to a print… </man>
	<description lang="en">Alvy steps forward, waving his hands in frustration, and stands facing the camera. </description>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Sighing and addressing the audience) What do you do when you get stuck in a movie line with a guy like this behind you ? I mean, it’s just maddening ! </alvy>
	<description lang="en">The man in line moves toward Alvy. Both address the audience now.</description>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : Wait a minute, why can’t I give my opinion ? It’s a free country !</man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : I mean, d- He can give you- Do you hafta give it so loud ? I mean, aren’t you ashamed to pontificate like that ? And-and the funny part of it is, M-Marshall McLuhan, you don-t know anything about Marshall McLuhan’s… Work !</alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Huh… </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : « Trentaine, électrique, cherche contacts avec femme intéressée par Mozart, James Joyce et sodomie. » (Il soupire) Comment ça : « Notre problème sexuel ? » </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Je t’en prie ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Tu ne t’en rends pas compte mais je suis presque normal, pour un gosse élevé à Brooklyn. </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : OK. Mille excuses. C’est mon problème sexuel ! Ça te va ? « Mon problème sexuel ! » </annie>
	<description lang="fr">l’homme qui est devant eux se retourne brièvement. </description>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Je n’ai pas lu cet ouvrage. Ce n’est pas du Truman Capote, non ? Je ne sais pas, mais c’est bien un sujet à la Capote ! </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Il semblerait… Que ce soit l’influence de la télévision… Car Marshall McLuhan attribue à ce medium privilégié une… Une haute, haute intensité… Tu comprends ? C’est un medium chaud. </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Si je m’écoutais, je l’assommerais avec une merde dans un bas de soie. </alvy>
	<description lang="fr">Alvy a un geste d’impuissance. Alors que l’homme continue à bavasser indistinctement, Alvy se met à avancer lentement vers la caméra. </description>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (il soupire et s’adresse directement à la caméra) : Qu’est- ce qu’on peut bien faire quand on est coincé dans une queue avec un gugusse pareil ? C’est vrai, quoi. Je deviens enragé. </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE (il avance vers Alvy) : Tout de même, j’ai bien le droit d’exprimer mon opinion. Nous sommes en démocratie. </man>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Mais oui ! Hé ! II… Il a le droit de nous… Faut-il que vous l’exprimiez si fort ? Enfin, c’est la honte, cette façon de pontifier sans arrêt ! Et… Et ce qui ne manque pas de sel, c’est qu’avec Ma…</man>
	<mcluhan lang="en">Marshall McLuhan, vous n’avez rien compris au vrai travail de McLuhan. </mcluhan>
	<man>MAN IN LINE : (Overlapping) Wait a minute ! Really ? Really ? I happen to teach a class at Columbia called « TV Media and Culture » ! So I think that my insights into Mr. McLuhan-well, have a great deal of validity. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : Oh, do yuh ? </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : Yes. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : Well, that’s funny, because I happen to have Mr. McLuhan right here. So… So, here, just let me-I mean, all right. Come over here… a second. Alvy gestures to the camera, which follows him and the man in line to the back of the crowded lobby. He moves over to a large stand-up movie poster and pulls Marshall McLuhan from behind the poster. </alvy>
	<man lang="en">MAN IN LINE : Oh. </man>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (To McLuhan) Tell him. </alvy>
	<mcluhan lang="en">MCLUHAN : (To the man in line) I hear-I heard what you were saying. You-you know nothing of my work. You mean, my whole fallacy is wrong. How you ever got to teach a course in anything is totally amazing. </mcluhan>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (To the camera) Boy, if life were only like this !</alvy>
	<description lang="en">Interior. Theater. A close-up of the screen showing faces of german soldiers. </description>
	<description lang="en">Credits appear over the faces of the soldiers : 	The Sorrow and The Pity 	© Cinema 5 Ltd., 1972 		© Marcel Ophuls, Andre Harris, 1969 Chronicle of a French town during the Occupation </description>
	<narrateur lang="en">NARRATOR’S VOICE : (Over credits and soldiers) June fourteenth, nineteen forty, the German army occupies Paris. All over the country, people are desperate for every available scrap of news. </narrateur>
	<description lang="en">– CUT TO - </description>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Vraiment ? Mh… Vraiment ? Figurez-vous qu’à l’université de Columbia, j’ai la chaire « Télévision Media et Culture ». Aussi bien, mes analyses au sujet de M. McLuhan font-elles autorité. </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Vous croyez ? </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Oui. </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : C’est amusant, parce que justement M. McLuhan est dans la queue ! </alvy>
	<description lang="fr">Alvy se dirige alors vers une affiche, et un homme sort de derrière le portant. </description>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Alors… Alors… Si vous permettez, je vous l’appelle, je vous l’appelle. Venez par ici. Une seconde. </alvy>
	<man lang="fr">HOMME DE LA FILE D’ATTENTE : Ahhhh… </man>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Dites-le-lui vous-même ! </alvy>
	<mcluhan lang="fr">MCLUHAN : J’ai enten… J’ai entendu ce que vous avez dit. Vous êtes passé à côté de mon travail. J’affirme que vous travestissez ma pensée. Que l’on vous ait confié une chaire, quelle qu’elle soit, c’est confondant ! </mcluhan>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (à la caméra) : Oh ! Le pied, si c’était ça, la vie !</alvy>
	<description lang="fr">Intérieur. Écran de cinéma. 		A l’écran, le générique défile sur des visages de soldats allemands : 		Le Chagrin et la pitié. 		Marcel Ophuls, André Harris. 		Chronique d’une ville française sous l’Occupation. </description>
	<narrateur lang="fr">VOIX DU NARRATEUR : Quatorze juin mil neuf cent quarante. L’armée allemande occupe Paris. Tous les Français, devant leur T.S.F., sont à l’affût de la moindre nouvelle. </narrateur>
	<description lang="en">Interior. Bedroom-Night. 		Annie is sitting up in bed reading. </description>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Offscreen) Boy, those guys in the French Resistance were really brave, you know ? Got to listen to Maurice Chevalier sing so much. </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : M’m, I don’t know, sometimes I ask myself how I’d stand up under torture. </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (Offscreen) You ? You kiddin’ ? (He moves into the frame, lying across the bed to touch Annie, who makes a face) If the Gestapo would take away your Bloomingdale’s charge card, you’d tell em everything. </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : That movie makes me feel guilty. </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : Yeah,’cause it’s supposed to. </alvy>
	<description lang="en">He starts kissing Annie’s arm. She gets annoyed and continues to read. </description>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : Alvy, I… </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : What-what-what-what’s the matter ? </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : I-you know, I don’t wanna. </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : (OverlappingAnnie, reacting) What-what-I dont’… It’s not natural ! We’re sleeping in a bed together. You know, it’s been a long time. </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : I know, well, it’s just that-you know, I mean, I-I- I-I gotta sing tomorrow night, so I have to rest my voice. ALVY : (Overlapping Annie again) It’s always some kind of an excuse. It’s- You know, you used to think that I was very sexy. What… When we first started going out, we had sex constantly… We’re-we’re probably listed in the Guinness Book of World Records. </annie>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : (Patting Alvy’s hand solicitously) I know. Well, Alvy, it’ll pass, it’ll pass, it’s just that I’m going through a phase, that’s all. </annie>
	<alvy lang="en">ALVY : M’m. </alvy>
	<annie lang="en">ANNIE : I mean, you’ve been married before, you know how things can get. You were very hot for Allison at first. </annie>
	<description lang="en">– CUT TO - </description>
	<description lang="fr">Intérieur. Chambre à coucher. Nuit. 		Annie, assise dans le lit, est en train de lire. </description>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (off) : Quand même, ils avaient vachement du cran, les résistants français ! Se taper du Maurice Chevalier ! ANNIE : Mmm… Tu sais, franchement, je me demande parfois si moi, je résisterais sous la torture. </alvy>
	<description lang="fr">Alvy s’allonge en travers du lit et heurte une Annie déjà grincheuse. </description>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY (off) : Toi ? Tu rigoles ? Si la (il entre dans le champ) Gestapo te prenait ta carte de crédit, je suis tranquille, tu passerais à table ! </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Ce film me donne mauvaise conscience. </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Normal ! Il est fait pour ! </alvy>
	<description lang="fr">Il se met à lui embrasser le bras, ce qui la dérange visiblement dans sa lecture. </description>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Alvy… Hh… Je… </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Qu’est-ce… Qu’est-ce… Mais… Qu’est-ce qu’il y a ? ANNIE : Je… Tu sais… Je n’ai pas envie. </alvy>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Quoi… Quoi ? Je ne… Mais c’est contre nature ! On dort ensemble dans le même lit, et tu avoueras que ça fait un bail… </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Je sais, mais il y a que, tu vois… Je… Je… Je… Dois chanter demain soir, et il ne faut pas que je fatigue mes cordes vocales ! </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Tu as toujours une bonne excuse. Pourtant, avant, tu allais jusqu’à me trouver très sexy. Tu te souviens, à nos débuts, c’est sans arrêt que nous… On doit même être dans le Livre des records ! </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE (elle caresse affectueusement la main d’Alvy) : Je sais. T’en fais pas, ça passera, ça passera. Je traverse une phase, c’est tout. </annie>
	<alvy lang="fr">ALVY : Mmm… </alvy>
	<annie lang="fr">ANNIE : Enfin, tu as été marié, Alvy, tu dois savoir ce genre de choses. Tu étais tout feu tout flamme pour Allison, au début. </annie>
</anniehall>
